<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sloan Nietert</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sloan Nietert</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Curious Connection between Quantum Information and Finite Geometry</title><link>/2020/01/21/a-curious-connection-between-quantum-information-and-finite-geometry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/21/a-curious-connection-between-quantum-information-and-finite-geometry/</guid><description>In this post, we’ll explore an interesting connection between finite affine planes, a well-studied class of combinatorial designs, and mutually unbiased bases, linear algebraic objects which play an important role in quantum information theory. In particular, we’ll see how both can be described by a common framework through which we can derive shared properties and proofs. What follows is based off of joint work with Mihály Weiner and Zsombor Szilágyi from my year in Budapest (see our pre-print on arXiv for more details and results).</description></item><item><title>Moser's Algorithm and the Lovász Local Lemma</title><link>/2019/12/26/mosers-algorithm-and-the-lov%C3%A1sz-local-lemma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/12/26/mosers-algorithm-and-the-lov%C3%A1sz-local-lemma/</guid><description>In this survey, we’ll examine the Lovász Local Lemma (LLL), a cornerstone of the probabilistic method, through the lens of theoretical computer science. This powerful tool was developed in the 70s by Hungarian mathematicians Lovász and Erdős to guarantee the existence of certain combinatorial structures1, and it has since been borrowed by computer scientists to prove results about satisfiability problems, graph colorings, tree codes, integer programming, and much more2.</description></item></channel></rss>